JAMES WOLFE

THE BEST CODER

✓ Wolfe.James.J96@gmail.com

(703)789-0919

Northern Virginia

Website Portfolio

SUMMARY

Computer Science graduate with a passion for problem-solving and learning, demonstrated experience in programming and customer service. Developed technical skill sets required to thrive in a professional work environment such as the AWS Cloud, web development, Linux, and computer technology troubleshooting.

SKILLS

o Hardware Troubleshooting o Joomla & WordPress o AWS Cloud Services o RedHat

o Sanding & Staining Wood o Java & HTML o SSH & CLI o Linux CLI

PROJECTS

Portfolios - Database Websites GitHub Repository

- Developed and maintained HTML and CSS websites using database and publishing services like AWS S3, Azure Container, Surge, and GitHub Pages.
- Created custom domain name with Google Domains and pointed the Ips in the DNS record to GitHub pages.

Serverless Application GitHub Repository

- Utilizing AWS Amplify CLI I launched an application and configured the server to connect to a GitHub repository.
- Application files were maintained and edited in Atom.

Headless Media Center

- Using a Raspberry Pi, I mounted an application called Volumio to the device and connected via hotspot to my phone.
- Set up respective devices using wireless keyboard, mouse, and wired monitor and connected the Raspberry Pi to Squire 4 Speakers.

Computer Building and Troubleshooting

- Set-up a Mid Tower computer after researching and budgeting for all necessary components and began troubleshooting boot issues then temperature issues utilizing POST solutions and bios configurations.
- Solved computer hardware and software issues for peers that resulted in replacing a power supply, ordering a larger case for cable management, and restoring a backup.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Woodworker Sue's Antiques

06/2021 — Present

After acquiring antique furniture and items, I refurbish and assemble pieces utilizing hand-on techniques then display a finished antique
in a variety of store locations selling the highest quality antique refurbished antiques.

Data Technician CORESTAFF SERVICES

11/2020 - 12/2020

 Worked through AWS Cloud troubleshooting tickets involving unable to POST and vital updates by rebooting servers, utilizing Linux update commands, reseating hardware and CAT5/6 cables, and other troubleshooting techniques.

Restaurant Server Mariachis TequliaRia & Restaurant

06/2018 - 01/2019

 Served customers while multi-tasking food orders, drink and chip refills, and station clean-up in a fast-paced environment to provide the best customer service.

Sale's Associate PetValu

09/2015 - 08/2017

- Faced with pet nutritional and health related issues I asked questions involving diet, exercise, symptoms, and allergies to accurately solve customer concern and did it effectively by utilizing critical thinking and communication skills.
- Volunteered with Homeward Trails, German Shepherd Rescue, and PetValu by feeding dogs and cats and cleaning cages.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner

7BEZSG02PNEEQ83D

Agile Scrum Fundamentals

ude.my/UC-800faeff-a669-4e5b-b802-3cbb834cdd2f

Linux Administration Bootcamp

ude.my/UC-fcd5c324-ad8c-4b70-a83d-b9712cb3b0f8

EDUCATION

Computer Science, Northern Virginia Community College Computer Science, Assembly Language, and Calculus II 2016-2020